<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="about_title">Dino Pedia</string>
    <string name="about_description">Dino Pedia Adalah Aplikasi seputar family dari Dinosaurus yang dikembangkan untuk UTS PAM</string>
    <string name="about_developer">Developer</string>
    <string name="about_developer_name">Wilona Diva Artha Simbolon</string>
    <string name="about_developer_mail">wilonadivaartha@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="app_name">Dino Pedia</string>
    <string name="info_gambar_dino">Picture</string>
    <string name="info_nama_dino">Family Name</string>
    <string name="info_deskripsi_dino">Description</string>
    <string name="info_periode_dino">Life Period</string>
    <string name="info_karakter_dino">Physical Characteristic</string>
    <string name="info_habitat_dino">Habitat and Environment</string>
    <string name="info_perilaku_dino">Behavior</string>
    <string name="info_klasifikasi_dino">Classification</string>
    <string name="gambar_detail_dino">Detail Picture</string>
    <string name="nama_detail_dino">Dinosaurs Name</string>
    <string name="deskripsi_detail_dino">Dino Description</string>
    <string name="karakteristik_detail_dino">Dino Characteristic</string>
    <string name="kelompok_detail_dino">Dino Group</string>
    <string name="habitat_detail_dino">Habitat Dino</string>
    <string name="makanan_detail_dino">Food</string>
    <string name="panjang_detail_dino">Dinos Length</string>
    <string name="tinggi_detail_dino">Dinos Height</string>
    <string name="bobot_detail_dino">Dinos Weight</string>
    <string name="kelemahan_detail_dino">Dinos Weakness</string>

    <!--gambar famili-->
    <string-array name="gambar_dino">
        <item>@drawable/famili1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili2</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili3</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili4</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili5</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili6</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili7</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili8</item>
    </string-array>

    <!--nama famili-->
    <string-array name="nama_dino">
        <item>Tyrannosauridae</item>
        <item>Sauropoda</item>
        <item>Stegosauridae</item>
        <item>Ceratopsia</item>
        <item>Ankylosauridae</item>
        <item>Ornithomimidae</item>
        <item>Hadrosauridae</item>
        <item>Theropoda</item>
    </string-array>


    <!--    deskripsi famili-->
    <string-array name="deskripsi_dino">
        <item>These were large, bipedal theropod dinosaurs with powerful jaws and sharp teeth. The most famous member of this family is Tyrannosaurus Rex.</item>
        <item>These were the largest land animals ever to have lived. They were herbivores with long necks, tails, and legs. Some well known sauropods include Brachiosaurus, Diplodocus, and Argentinosaurus.</item>
        <item>These were herbivores with bony plates and spikes along their backs. They had small brains and were relatively slow-moving. Some examples include Stegosaurus, Kentrosaurus, and Dacentrurus.</item>
        <item>These were herbivores with horns and a bony frill around their necks. They had strong jaws and were well-adapted for grazing. Some ceratopsians include Triceratops, Centrosaurus, and Styracosaurus.</item>
        <item>These were heavily armored herbivores with bony plates and spikes covering their bodies. They had short legs and were slow-moving. Some ankylosaurs include Ankylosaurus, Nodosaurus, and Pinacosaurus.</item>
        <item>These were fast, bipedal dinosaurs with long legs and beaks. They were probably omnivores and may have been able to run very fast. Some ornithomimids include Gallimimus, Ornithomimus, and Deinonychus.</item>
        <item>These were herbivores with duck-billed snouts and crests on their heads. They had powerful jaws and were well-adapted for eating tough plants. Some hadrosaurs include Parasaurolophus, Corythosaurus, and Edmontosaurus.</item>
        <item>This is a large and diverse group of dinosaurs that includes tyrannosaurs, birds, and many other bipedal dinosaurs. Some theropods were carnivores, while others were herbivores or omnivores.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="periode_dino">
        <item>Late Cretaceous (99-66 million years ago)</item>
        <item>Late Jurassic – Late Cretaceous (157–66 million years ago)</item>
        <item>Late Jurassic - Early Cretaceous (157-100 million years ago)</item>
        <item>Early Cretaceous - Late Cretaceous (145-66 million years ago)</item>
        <item>Early Cretaceous - Late Cretaceous (145-66 million years ago)</item>
        <item>Late Cretaceous (99-66 million years ago)</item>
        <item>Late Cretaceous (76-66 million years ago)</item>
        <item>Late Triassic - Late Cretaceous (230-66 million years ago)</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="karakter_dino">
        <item>These were enormous, two-legged predators with the most powerful jaws and teeth of any land animal. They reigned supreme as apex predators during their time. (Examples: Tyrannosaurus Rex, Tarbosaurus,</item>
        <item>The largest land creatures ever to have walked the Earth! These herbivores possessed incredibly long necks, tails, and legs, allowing them to reach and consume vast quantities of foliage. (Examples: Brachiosaurus, Diplodocus, Argentinosaurus)</item>
        <item>Herbivores with a distinctive appearance, these dinosaurs sported bony plates and spikes along their backs, likely for defense. Their brains were relatively small, and their movement was presumably slow. (Examples: Stegosaurus, Kentrosaurus, Dacentrurus)</item>
        <item>Equipped with horns and a bony frill around their necks, these herbivores were well-adapted for grazing. Their powerful jaws could chomp through tough vegetation. (Examples: Triceratops, Centrosaurus, Styracosaurus)</item>
        <item>Heavily armored herbivores, these dinosaurs were like walking tanks with bony plates and spikes covering their entire bodies. Short legs meant they were slow-moving, but their armor provided excellent protection from predators. (Examples: Ankylosaurus, Nodosaurus, Pinacosaurus)</item>
        <item>These fast, bipedal dinosaurs were built for speed with long legs and beaks. They were likely omnivores and may have been capable of incredibly fast running. (Examples: Gallimimus, Ornithomimus, Deinonychus)</item>
        <item>These herbivores had unique duck-billed snouts and crests on their heads. Their powerful jaws allowed them to efficiently eat tough plants. (Examples: Parasaurolophus, Corythosaurus, Edmontosaurus)</item>
        <item>Encompassing a vast and diverse group, this family includes tyrannosaurs, birds, and many other bipedal dinosaurs. Theropods exhibited a range of dietary preferences, with some being carnivores, herbivores, or even omnivores.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="habitat_dino">
        <item>These large predators lived in a variety of habitats, including forests, floodplains, and coastal areas.</item>
        <item>These giants favored open habitats like savannas and woodlands, where they could browse on abundant vegetation.</item>
        <item>These herbivores preferred forests and wooded areas, where their armored bodies and camouflage provided protection from predators.</item>
        <item>These dinosaurs thrived in diverse habitats, ranging from coastal plains to inland forests and even semi-arid environments.</item>
        <item>Their armored bodies made them well-suited for a variety of habitats, including forests, deserts, and even near bodies of water.</item>
        <item>These fast-moving dinosaurs inhabited open habitats like grasslands and savannas, where they could pursue prey or escape predators.</item>
        <item>These herbivores were found in a wide range of habitats, including forests, floodplains, and coastal areas.</item>
        <item>As a diverse group, theropods occupied a variety of habitats, from forests and deserts to coastal regions and even the polar regions.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="perilaku_dino">
        <item>These fearsome predators likely employed a mix of hunting strategies, acting as both active hunters in packs and opportunistic scavengers. Cannibalism might have also occurred within these groups. Interestingly, some evidence suggests they may have cared for their young.</item>
        <item>Imagine gentle giants roaming in herds! These colossal herbivores likely undertook long migrations to find food and may have communicated using low-frequency sounds inaudible to human ears. Building nests and caring for their young are possibilities based on available evidence.</item>
        <item>Primarily solitary or living in small groups, these herbivores munched on leaves, fruits, and seeds. Their most prominent feature, the spiky tail (thagomizer), served as a formidable defense mechanism. Whether they were active during the day or night remains under debate.</item>
        <item>Safety in numbers! These herbivores found protection in herds while grazing on tough plants. Their horns and elaborate frills functioned for both defense against predators and visual display.  Theres a possibility they cooperatively raised their young within the herd.</item>
        <item>Picture heavily armored tanks lumbering across the landscape. Solitary and slow-moving, these herbivores fed on low-growing plants. Their primary defense was their impressive armor, although their activity patterns (day or night) are still being unraveled.</item>
        <item>Built for speed and agility, these dinosaurs were likely adept predators of small animals and insects. They might have lived in flocks, and some theories suggest they potentially built nests and cared for their young.</item>
        <item>Herding provided safety for these herbivores as they grazed on tough plants. Their unique head crests might have been used for communication and display within the herd. Similar to Ceratopsians, they might have exhibited cooperative breeding behavior.</item>
        <item>Encompassing a diverse range of behaviors, theropods included predators, scavengers, and even herbivores. Social structures also varied, with some living in packs and others being solitary. Nest building and parental care likely differed among the various theropod species.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="klasifikasi_dino">
        <item>Theropoda: Including bipedal (two-legged) carnivores like Tyrannosaurus rex, Velociraptor, and modern birds.</item>
        <item>Sauropodomorpha: Encompassing long-necked herbivores like Brachiosaurus, Diplodocus, and Argentinosaurus.</item>
        <item>Neornithischia: Including bipedal and quadrupedal herbivores like Triceratops, Stegosaurus, and Ankylosaurus.</item>
        <item>Ornithopoda: Including bipedal herbivores like Hadrosaurs and Iguanodon.</item>
        <item>Suborder Theropoda: Tyrannosauridae (Tyrannosaurus rex), Velociraptoridae (Velociraptor), Dromaeosauridae (Deinonychus), Troodontidae (Troodon), Archaeopterygidae (Archaeopteryx)</item>
        <item>Suborder Sauropodomorpha: Brachiosauridae (Brachiosaurus), Diplodocidae (Diplodocus), Titanosauridae (Argentinosaurus), Camarasauridae (Camarasaurus)</item>
        <item>Suborder Neornithischia: Ceratopsidae (Triceratops), Stegosauridae (Stegosaurus), Ankylosauridae (Ankylosaurus), Pachycephalosauridae (Pachycephalosaurus)</item>
        <item>Suborder Ornithopoda: Hadrosauridae (Hadrosaurus), Iguanodontidae (Iguanodon), Hypsilophodontidae (Hypsilophodon)</item>
    </string-array>


    <!--    detail-->

    <!-- gambar detail famili-->

    <!--nama detail famili-->
    <string-array name="nama_detail_dino">
        <item>Tyrannosaurus rex</item>
        <item>Tarbosaurus bataar</item>
        <item>Brachiosaurus altithorax</item>
        <item>Diplodocus longus</item>
        <item>Stegosaurus stenops</item>
        <item>Kentrosaurus aethiopicus</item>
        <item>Triceratops horridus</item>
        <item>Pentaceratops sternbergi</item>
        <item>Ankylosaurus magniventris</item>
        <item>Euoplocephalus tutus</item>
        <item>Gallimimus bullatus</item>
        <item>Struthiomimus altus</item>
        <item>Parasaurolophus walkeri</item>
        <item>Corythosaurus casuarius</item>
        <item>Velociraptor mongoliensis</item>
        <item>Deinonychus antirrhopus</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="gambar_detail_dino">
        <item>@drawable/famiili1_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili1_2</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili2_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili2_2</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili3_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili3_2</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili4_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili4_2</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili5_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili5_2</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili6_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili6_2</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili7_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili7_2</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili8_1</item>
        <item>@drawable/famili8_2</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="deskripsi_detail_dino">
        <item>The Tyrannosaurus rex is one of the largest land predators. It lived during the late Cretaceous period. Known for its powerful bite and short arms.</item>
        <item>The Tarbosaurus bataar is a close relative of the Tyrannosaurus rex, found in Asia during the late Cretaceous period. It shares many similarities with T. rex.</item>
        <item>The Brachiosaurus altithorax is a massive herbivore with a long neck and tall stature. It lived during the Late Jurassic period and likely fed on vegetation from tall trees.</item>
        <item>The Diplodocus longus is a long-necked, long-tailed dinosaur from the Late Jurassic period. It had a small head relative to its body size and was a herbivore.</item>
        <item>The Stegosaurus stenops is known for its distinctive double row of bony plates along its back and spikes on its tail. It lived during the Late Jurassic period and was an herbivore.</item>
        <item>The Kentrosaurus aethiopicus is a smaller relative of the Stegosaurus, characterized by its long spikes on its body. It lived during the Late Jurassic period in Africa.</item>
        <item>The Triceratops horridus is a well-known dinosaur with three horns on its face and a frill behind its head. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period and was an herbivore.</item>
        <item>The Pentaceratops sternbergi is a large ceratopsian dinosaur with five horns on its head. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period in North America.</item>
        <item>The Ankylosaurus magniventris is a heavily armored dinosaur with a club-like tail. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period and was primarily a herbivore.</item>
        <item>The Euoplocephalus tutus is another armored dinosaur similar to the Ankylosaurus. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period in North America.</item>
        <item>The Gallimimus bullatus is a fast and agile dinosaur with a long, slender body. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period and was likely an omnivore.</item>
        <item>The Struthiomimus altus is another fast dinosaur resembling an ostrich. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period and was likely an omnivore.</item>
        <item>The Parasaurolophus walkeri is known for its distinctive crest on its head, which may have been used for communication. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period and was an herbivore.</item>
        <item>The Corythosaurus casuarius is another duck-billed dinosaur with a crest on its head. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period in North America.</item>
        <item>The Velociraptor mongoliensis is a small, agile dinosaur known for its speed and intelligence. It lived during the Late Cretaceous period in Asia and was likely a carnivore.</item>
        <item>The Deinonychus antirrhopus is another small, agile dinosaur closely related to the Velociraptor. It lived during the Early Cretaceous period in North America and was likely a carnivore.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="karakteristik_detail_dino">
        <item>Large size, powerful bite, short arms</item>
        <item>Large size, powerful bite, similar to T. rex</item>
        <item>Massive herbivore, long neck, tall stature</item>
        <item>Long-necked, long-tailed herbivore</item>
        <item>Distinctive bony plates, spiked tail</item>
        <item>Small relative of Stegosaurus, long spikes on body</item>
        <item>Three horns on face, frill behind head</item>
        <item>Large ceratopsian, five horns on head</item>
        <item>Heavily armored, club-like tail</item>
        <item>Armored dinosaur, similar to Ankylosaurus</item>
        <item>Fast and agile, long, slender body</item>
        <item>Fast dinosaur resembling an ostrich</item>
        <item>Distinctive crest on head, likely for communication</item>
        <item>Duck-billed dinosaur with crest on head</item>
        <item>Small, agile dinosaur known for speed and intelligence</item>
        <item>Small, agile dinosaur closely related to Velociraptor</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="kelompok_detail_dino">
        <item>Theropoda</item>
        <item>Theropoda</item>
        <item>Sauropoda</item>
        <item>Sauropoda</item>
        <item>Stegosauridae</item>
        <item>Stegosauridae</item>
        <item>Ceratopsidae</item>
        <item>Ceratopsidae</item>
        <item>Ankylosauria</item>
        <item>Ankylosauria</item>
        <item>Ornithomimidae</item>
        <item>Ornithomimidae</item>
        <item>Hadrosauridae</item>
        <item>Hadrosauridae</item>
        <item>Dromaeosauridae</item>
        <item>Dromaeosauridae</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="habitat_detail_dino">
        <item>Forests and plains</item>
        <item>Forests and plains</item>
        <item>Plains and swamps</item>
        <item>Plains and forests</item>
        <item>Open woodlands</item>
        <item>Plains and forests</item>
        <item>Forests and plains</item>
        <item>Plains</item>
        <item>Plains and forests</item>
        <item>Plains and forests</item>
        <item>Plains</item>
        <item>Plains</item>
        <item>Plains and forests</item>
        <item>Plains and forests</item>
        <item>Forests</item>
        <item>Forests</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="makanan_detail_dino">
        <item>Other dinosaurs, carrion</item>
        <item>Other dinosaurs, carrion</item>
        <item>Vegetation, leaves</item>
        <item>Vegetation, leaves</item>
        <item>Vegetation, ferns</item>
        <item>Vegetation, leaves</item>
        <item>Vegetation, plants</item>
        <item>Vegetation, plants</item>
        <item>Vegetation, plants</item>
        <item>Vegetation, plants</item>
        <item>Small animals, plants</item>
        <item>Small animals, plants</item>
        <item>Vegetation, plants</item>
        <item>Vegetation, plants</item>
        <item>Small animals, carrion</item>
        <item>Small animals, carrion</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="panjang_detail_dino">
        <item>12.3 meters</item>
        <item>11 meters</item>
        <item>23-26 meters</item>
        <item>24-27 meters</item>
        <item>9 meters</item>
        <item>4-5 meters</item>
        <item>9 meters</item>
        <item>7-8 meters</item>
        <item>6-8 meters</item>
        <item>6-7 meters</item>
        <item>6 meters</item>
        <item>4-5 meters</item>
        <item>9-10 meters</item>
        <item>9 meters</item>
        <item>1.8 meters</item>
        <item>3.4 meters</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="tinggi_detail_dino">
        <item>5-6 meters</item>
        <item>5-6 meters</item>
        <item>15 meters</item>
        <item>8 meters</item>
        <item>4 meters</item>
        <item>2.5 meters</item>
        <item>3 meters</item>
        <item>3 meters</item>
        <item>1.5 meters</item>
        <item>2 meters</item>
        <item>2 meters</item>
        <item>2.5 meters</item>
        <item>4 meters</item>
        <item>4 meters</item>
        <item>0.5 meters</item>
        <item>1 meter</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="bobot_detail_dino">
        <item>8-9 tons</item>
        <item>5-6 tons</item>
        <item>30-80 tons</item>
        <item>10-20 tons</item>
        <item>2-3 tons</item>
        <item>1-2 tons</item>
        <item>6-12 tons</item>
        <item>5-6 tons</item>
        <item>4-6 tons</item>
        <item>2-3 tons</item>
        <item>1 ton</item>
        <item>1 ton</item>
        <item>2-3 tons</item>
        <item>2-3 tons</item>
        <item>15-20 kg</item>
        <item>50-70 kg</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="kelemahan_detail_dino">
        <item>Short arms, slow movement</item>
        <item>Short arms, slow movement</item>
        <item>Slow movement, vulnerability due to size</item>
        <item>Slow movement, vulnerability due to size</item>
        <item>Slow movement, small brain</item>
        <item>Small size, vulnerability to predators</item>
        <item>Large size, vulnerability to predators</item>
        <item>Large size, vulnerability to predators</item>
        <item>Slow movement, vulnerability due to armor placement</item>
        <item>Slow movement, vulnerability due to armor placement</item>
        <item>Fragile bones, vulnerability to predators</item>
        <item>Fragile bones, vulnerability to predators</item>
        <item>Long crest, vulnerability to predators</item>
        <item>Long crest, vulnerability to predators</item>
        <item>Small size, vulnerability to larger predators</item>
        <item>Small size, vulnerability to larger predators</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="start_dino">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>10</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>14</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="end_dino">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>13</item>
        <item>15</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>